<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>In a cave, with a box of scraps</title><description>An account of my journey to become a software engineer. </description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 13:50:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>QuickSort</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I just figured out quicksort today. Let's see if I can make sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quicksort is a sorting algorithm used to put items in order and is considered one of the most efficient ways of doing so (average run time &lt;code&gt;O(n log n)&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this example list, I'll&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/algorithms/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">59732d0e-fdeb-440f-965b-48cfe58fb186</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 13:50:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I just figured out quicksort today. Let's see if I can make sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quicksort is a sorting algorithm used to put items in order and is considered one of the most efficient ways of doing so (average run time &lt;code&gt;O(n log n)&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this example list, I'll describe how it works &lt;br&gt;
9 0 8 7 3 2 1 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with one of the values in the list. By convention, we pick the last number, "5". We call this our &lt;strong&gt;pivot.&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The goal is now to put everything lower than the pivot to the left of it and everything higher than the pivot to the right of it. We do this in two partitions, the leftPartition and the rightPartition. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leftPartition will be 0 3 2 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rightPartition will be 9 8 7 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we now have 0 3 2 1 || 9 8 7 [5]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;insert the 5 into the front-end of the rightpartition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 3 2 1 || 5 9 8 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rinse and repeat for the two smaller partitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Moved to SF - I start tomorrow</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've already fallen into the trap that most of these bloggers do...I've become super busy. Some of what prevents me from writing is wanting to be awake and careful with my words. Perhaps if I simple take a stream-of-consciousness approach to writing, I'll generate more content...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove down&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/moved-to-sf-i-start-tomorrw/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">9805b9ea-9eff-4f78-b5ba-514aae0e38c1</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 23:22:28 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I've already fallen into the trap that most of these bloggers do...I've become super busy. Some of what prevents me from writing is wanting to be awake and careful with my words. Perhaps if I simple take a stream-of-consciousness approach to writing, I'll generate more content...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove down to SF last Saturday and stayed with my Dad and Deb. Christine met me there and we explored Berkeley a bit as well as the city. She'll join me in the middle of next month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now living in Cohort X, a housing option created specifically for bootcamp students. All of my now roommates are 20 and 30 somethings; and super techie. We'll sit around and discuss coding, math, or philosophy. It's pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place is in the north mission on 15th and Folsom. The immediate area is fine, but I dread having to take the 16th and Mission BART. Having lived in Seattle, I've been around a few homeless and alternative lifestyle people. The mission is a big step up in terms of volume of homeless and range of behaviors. Fortunately, they actually seem more polite here. It will continue to be a learning and growth opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I walked home from a bar called 21st amendment after a meet-up with my cohort. The first part of the walk through SOMA was great, but as you pass the hall of justice and the two dozen "bail bonds" offices, it becomes uncomfortable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm restless. I can't believe that I start tomorrow at 8:30 AM. I constantly feel like I need to be studying; that somehow if I'm not working, I'm jeopardizing my future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm heading to my Dad and Deb's tonight for dinner. Hopefully I'll get back early enough to get to bed on time, but I've also taken two separate 90 minute naps. My body's clock is all sorts of off and I don't have time to reset it before we begin. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then...here we go. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Data structures</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've spent some time coding out classic data structures. While I thought that plopping my code below was what I should do...I think I'd rather try to describe these concepts in plain, old english. Email me if you want the source code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll briefly cover the following:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked list&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/data-structures/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">bab506a1-5230-49f3-a558-8e9a6f12a335</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 18:10:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I've spent some time coding out classic data structures. While I thought that plopping my code below was what I should do...I think I'd rather try to describe these concepts in plain, old english. Email me if you want the source code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll briefly cover the following:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked list
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Has a list of &lt;strong&gt;nodes&lt;/strong&gt; with the following properties
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; - or other information it's holding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;next&lt;/code&gt; - the location of the next node that has information&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the list itself holds access to the &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; node as well as methods like add, remove, sort, etc....&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doubly linked list
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;like the above, but it keeps track of previous nodes as well
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;node&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;next&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;prev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;list&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;tail&lt;/code&gt;, other methods&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Search Tree
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a tree where values lower than a node are on the left and values higher are on the right&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;nodes with several connections and possible directions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a graph, to me, felt a lot like a classic flow chart. Anything can connect to anything, if it makes sense&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* here is some of the code from before *&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linked List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;class Node {  
  constructor(data, next){
    this.data = data;
    this.next = next || null;
  }
}
class LinkedList {  
  constructor(){
    this.head = null;
    this.length = 0;
  }

  add(data){
    var node = new Node(data);
    var current = this.head;
    if(this.head !== null){
      while(current.next){
        current = current.next;
      }
      current.next = node;
    } else {
      this.head = node;
    }
    this.length++;
    return this.head;
  }

  remove(index){
    if(index &amp;lt; 0 || index &amp;gt; this.length) return "ERROR";

    if(this.head === null) return "Nothing to remove";
    if(index === 0){
      this.head = this.head.next;
    } else {
      var current = this.head;
      while(index &amp;gt; 1){
        current = current.next;
        index--;
      }
      current.next = current.next.next
      return this.head
    }
  }
}

var newList = new LinkedList();  
newList.add(1);  
newList.add(2);  
newList.add(3);  
newList.remove(0);  
console.log(newList.head);


function generateLinkedLists(arrayofData){  
  var nodeStorage = {};
  arrayofData.forEach((data, i) =&amp;gt; {
    nodeStorage['node' + i] = new Node(data);
    if(i !== 0){
      nodeStorage['node' + (i - 1)].next = nodeStorage['node' + i]
    }
  });
  return nodeStorage['node0'];
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doubly Linked List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;class Node {  
  constructor(data, next, prev){
    this.data = data;
    this.next = next || null;
    this.prev = prev || null;
  }
}
class DoublyLinkedList {  
  constructor(){
    this.head = null;
    this.tail = null
    this.length = 0;
  }

  add(data){
    var node = new Node(data);
    var current = this.head;
    if(this.head !== null){
      while(current.next){
        current = current.next;
      }
      current.next = node;
      node.prev = current;
      this.tail = node;
    } else {
      this.head = node;
    }
    this.length++;
    return this.head;
  }

  remove(index){
    if(index &amp;lt; 0 || index &amp;gt; this.length) return "ERROR";

    if(this.head === null) return "Nothing to remove";
    if(index === 0){
      this.head = this.head.next;
      this.head.prev = null;
    } else {
      var current = this.head;
      while(index &amp;gt; 1){
        current = current.next;
        index--;
      }
      current.next = current.next.next;
      current.next.next.prev = current.next;
      return this.head
    }
  }
}

var newList = new DoublyLinkedList();  
newList.add(1);  
newList.add(2);  
newList.add(3);  
newList.remove(0);  
console.log(newList.head);  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Last week of work, moving to Cali, seeing Christine</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Here are thoughts in my head as I sit here at my desk on a Wednesday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am halfway through the last week of work for Starbucks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night at Foundation Crossfit, Tina, Sarah, and Margot comforted me about my situation. I admire those women greatly, and all the more&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/last-week-of-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">e537a36e-5a2f-464a-b22b-affb780c1afb</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 17:43:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here are thoughts in my head as I sit here at my desk on a Wednesday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am halfway through the last week of work for Starbucks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night at Foundation Crossfit, Tina, Sarah, and Margot comforted me about my situation. I admire those women greatly, and all the more so for their compassion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate saying goodbye; and it's not because saying goodbye is too emotional or sad. It just seems odd to me to make all this time now to connect with people. A relationship is built on the daily actions, activities, and sharing with one another. Whether or not we have a chance to "say goodbye" doesn't affect that. It's "see you when I see you"...which is the way it is most of the time. You never know what will happen to you or others. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've told all of the teams that I work with that my last day will be Friday. There's going to be a large coffee tasting for all of the great people that I've met here. I have 1:1 connections with people who won't be able to attend. Some people are shocked, others are excited, and everyone is supportive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I had been ready to consider moving for bootcamp in June, the decision to bootcamp right now was influenced by Christine's (my girlfriend) situation. For those that don't know, Christine had a neurological episode that we believe is a form of relapsing-remitting MS. I took her to the hospital on 4/25, where we heard the diagnosis for the first time. We spent the next several days in an adrenaline haze. I don't remember much of the week. We revisited the hospital many, many times...struggling through the administrative gauntlet as we tried to better understand how to manage her condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week after her attack, she began to steadily improve and her grandma came to take care of her. Granny Bazeghi took her back to Santa Barbara about a week later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been apart for a couple of weeks, which is not very fun, we thought about how we'd manage future situations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to live in California. Our families and support structures are all there. We're going to establish home as a place neither of us have ever lived. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christine has continued to improve and is even driving herself to coffee shops now. We'll meet up this Saturday and spend the week together before my bootcamp begins. The plan is that she'll join in mid-July, or potentially earlier (pending her recovery). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're doing a lot all at once. With Christine's attack, I've decided I'd rather do bootcamp right now and be closer to her. Simultaneously, she will do her remote program as she recovers. In addition, we're continuing to see neurologists while we adjust to life in California. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both laughed last night at how poor we are. This is a hard time financially, but we're hoping this will be a fun time to look back on. That time when we were poor and had to ask our family members for money. Our families have been wonderfully supportive, and that's a gift. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onto the next adventure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/05/IMG_0307.jpg" alt="" a="" pic="" of="" christine="" and="" me""=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>My journey to HR</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I think it's important to note that I did not pass the technical interview the first time...or the second time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting into HR required a lot of studying. I &lt;strong&gt;did not&lt;/strong&gt; remotely think that I would be this far along before even starting a bootcamp. It really seems like&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/my-journey-to-hr/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">bb08dc59-df15-4a35-a46d-b86c5a2ac048</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:44:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I think it's important to note that I did not pass the technical interview the first time...or the second time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting into HR required a lot of studying. I &lt;strong&gt;did not&lt;/strong&gt; remotely think that I would be this far along before even starting a bootcamp. It really seems like  you need to be able to make use of all the free resources out there, and then HR will fill in the gaps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first applied in January 2016. I bombed the technical interview. I got so nervous and choked up. My mind went blank. It was not my best work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went to studying. I studied higher order functions, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Node, Express...I went way overboard on non-essentials. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I needed more guidance and entered Fulcrum. Fulcrum is amazing. I highly recommend it. Fulcrum helps you get up to speed on exactly what you need to know in regards to Javascript fundamentals. If you're serious about attending Hack Reactor, I can't recommend Fulcrum highly enough. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared like crazy for the technical interview and memorized many many underscore functions. Bad idea. They care about problem solving, not memorization. I did not pass the second interview: I choked, I panicked, I blanked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's an underrated and under-appreciated skill that I had yet to develop: can you do technical work while someone else who has the answers judges you? Can you be a humble and vulnerable learner? Can you adapt to a teacher's corrections? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice this&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made me succeed in my third interview is repeated practice of technical interviews. I reached out to all of my dev friends and did skype as well as whiteboard interviews (that were above my skill level). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Conrad Wimberly and Landon Schropp, two of my practice interviewers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I gradually became more comfortable with that type of coding. It's different, treat it as a separate skill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps! &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>BackboneJS and ES6 application</title><description>&lt;p&gt;What I need to understand is concepts, not how to implement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Matthew Platts for these videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJwgIth1I_w"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJwgIth1I_w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch all 3 of these videos to begin to conceptualize what Backbone JS is about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's my current understanding: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BackboneJS is an ultra-lightweight, un-opinionated,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/backbonejs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02f38177-29d3-454f-a534-37750bf9dfc0</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:35:09 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What I need to understand is concepts, not how to implement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Matthew Platts for these videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJwgIth1I_w"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJwgIth1I_w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch all 3 of these videos to begin to conceptualize what Backbone JS is about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's my current understanding: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BackboneJS is an ultra-lightweight, un-opinionated, front-end framework. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It creates representations of your database within the javascript environment. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;These representations are attached to items on the DOM so that as you change the JS representations, the DOM is also updated appropriately. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the models have changed, Backbone sends an AJAX request to the server to make the appropriate changes in the database.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my process of familiarization, I also happened to learn about ES6 arrow functions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you watch the videos, you'll notice that Matt needs to create static references to &lt;code&gt;this&lt;/code&gt;. He does this by doing &lt;code&gt;var self = this&lt;/code&gt; and then referencing &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;. With ES6, we actually have a fix for this issue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the code block below, I've created two methods that showcase how es5 handles &lt;code&gt;this&lt;/code&gt; versus es6. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;var _ = require("underscore");  
var people = [  
  {name: "Alex", age: 25},
  {name: "Christine", age: 26}
];

var methods = {  
  es5: function(){
    _.each(people, function(person){
      console.log(this); // window
    });
  },

  es6: function(){
    _.each(people, (person) =&amp;gt; {
      console.log(this); // window
    });
  }
}

methods.es5(); // window/global object  
methods.es6(); // methods object  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll continue to update this with more learnings! &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Pre - HR Learning Plan</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As I described in my last post, CS knowledge is something I want to get ahead of. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's jot down a few areas to study and come up with a plan. PS - if no one reads this then I'm really just talking to myself; which isn't abnormal, I'm just&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/pre-hr-learning-plan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">c44cb5a7-2f49-49ee-959f-3b55656dbeea</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:24:38 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As I described in my last post, CS knowledge is something I want to get ahead of. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's jot down a few areas to study and come up with a plan. PS - if no one reads this then I'm really just talking to myself; which isn't abnormal, I'm just realizing it now :). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;  
  &lt;li&gt;Computer Science-y Things&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt; 
        &lt;li&gt;Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt; 
          &lt;li&gt;Search&lt;/li&gt; 
          &lt;li&gt;Sort&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Data Structures&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;ul&gt; 
          &lt;li&gt;Lists, trees, graphs&lt;/li&gt; 
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review of Precourse&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt; 
        &lt;li&gt;Underbar&lt;/li&gt; 
        &lt;li&gt;Recursion&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Code Wars&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Front End (HTML, CSS, jQuery)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Framework Familiarization &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt; 
        &lt;li&gt;BackboneJS&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;AngularJS&lt;/li&gt; 
        &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll try to make a post reviewing each of these...but they may just be built slowly over time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Resources &lt;br&gt;
- &lt;a href="http://khan4019.github.io/front-end-Interview-Questions/"&gt;http://khan4019.github.io/front-end-Interview-Questions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>It's a marathon, not a sprint...I sprint marathons</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONTEXT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college (and in a fraternity), people really seemed to like Jimmy Tatro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video is ridiculous. So just skip to 2:50 so that you can be in on the inside joke. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fbsk127TnnE"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fbsk127TnnE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONTENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, well now that&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/its-a-marathon-not-a-sprint-i-sprint-marathons/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">79a4e4ab-a3d3-4f74-a2da-9c52d44378b1</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 20:16:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONTEXT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college (and in a fraternity), people really seemed to like Jimmy Tatro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video is ridiculous. So just skip to 2:50 so that you can be in on the inside joke. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fbsk127TnnE"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fbsk127TnnE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONTENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, well now that we're on the same page(and becoming fast friends!)...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hack Reactor is known to be intense and I want to be over-prepared. It is a marathon, but if I can run 2 or 3 miles at a 15 minute pace before the race even starts, then I might be able to take a few breaths. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My degree is in Chemical Engineering and though I took a CS class, I really don't remember it. Today, I am going to try to cram in some CS knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask my CS friends what I should learn...they say: "algorithms and data structures". That's a starting point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's break down how to approach these items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithms
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Structures
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Singly and Doubly linked lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack and Queue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary search trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what all of these are...so I am going to make another post with a learning plan. This post will hopefully capture any knowledge that I gain along the way!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>I figured this out...after fumbling a bit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Well.. I've mastered blogs. Or at least how to repeatedly type &lt;code&gt;buster deploy&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to this article here : &lt;a href="http://blog.sunnyg.io/2015/09/24/ghost-with-github/"&gt;http://blog.sunnyg.io/2015/09/24/ghost-with-github/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few words of caution &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make  sure to install nvm and use node v 0.12.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you already had a username.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/i-figured-this-out-after-fumbling-a-bit/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">125cb210-ca6b-46bf-8a09-4dd4a8e08a01</guid><dc:creator>Alex Stark</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 22:52:53 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Well.. I've mastered blogs. Or at least how to repeatedly type &lt;code&gt;buster deploy&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to this article here : &lt;a href="http://blog.sunnyg.io/2015/09/24/ghost-with-github/"&gt;http://blog.sunnyg.io/2015/09/24/ghost-with-github/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few words of caution &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make  sure to install nvm and use node v 0.12.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you already had a username.github.io repository, go ahead and delete it. Start a new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this blog will be to capture my learnings as a part of the HR 44 cohort! I am excited, nervous, and extremely ready to go...&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>